<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content  Outreach on Will Nye - The SEO Guy</title>
    <link>https://www.williamnye.co.uk/categories/content--outreach/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content  Outreach on Will Nye - The SEO Guy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.williamnye.co.uk/categories/content--outreach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence The Psychology of Persuasion – Outreach Takeaways</title>
      <link>https://www.williamnye.co.uk/influence-psychology-persuasion-outreach-takeaways/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.williamnye.co.uk/influence-psychology-persuasion-outreach-takeaways/</guid>
      <description>Recently, i’ve been trying to better understand what constitutes ‘good outreach’ in an attempt to increase response rates and overall placements. Ignoring the quality of the actual content being outreached — which, I believe, will always be the number one factor — there appear to be three main components. These are:
1. Outreach targets: The quality of the contact list, e.g. relevency to the writer/site.
2. The Pitch: The language used in the initial email — subject line, copy, length of copy, link inclusion, attachment inclusion, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What SEOs Can Learn From #TheDress</title>
      <link>https://www.williamnye.co.uk/seos-can-learn-thedress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.williamnye.co.uk/seos-can-learn-thedress/</guid>
      <description>Unless you’ve been living under a rock for the past week, you’ve probably read or heard something about #TheDress. The debate went viral last Thursday, resulting in a massive influx of publicity for the retailer Roman Originals and an overnight 347% increase in sales for the garment in question.
Yet, beyond an initial spike in product interest, what will the legacy of #TheDress be for the brand? Additionally, based on previous academic research, what can we learn from the stories success?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>